RG 074:037, Howland F. Atwood Genealogical Papers
Connecticut State Library
Howland F. Atwood genealogical papers
circa 1940-1977
Connecticut State Library
Atwood, Howland F.
16.5 cubic feet
Genealogical material on the Atwood family and collateral lines.
RG074_037
1977-002
Biographical Note
Howland F. Atwood was born in 1918 and became interested in genealogy in the 1930s (Howland F. Atwood letter to Lizette Pelletier, March 2, 1994, Connecticut State Archives RG 074 file).
Scope and Content
Genealogical material on the Atwood family and collateral lines. Some material dates from the nineteenth century.
Related Material
Atwood family: History and Genealogy Unit Special Genealogical File, 1932-1992
Index Terms
Persons:
Atwood, Howland F.
Family Names:
Atwood family
Places:
Connecticut -- Genealogy; Vermont -- Genealogy
Document Types:
Correspondence; Genealogies; News clippings; Photographs
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Provenance
Donated to the Connecticut State Library by Howland F. Atwood. The first accession of this collection was received on September 21, 1977.
Container List
- Papers
  - ATWOOD. English Ancestry (Box 1, Volume I)
  - John WOOD-ATWOOD of Plymouth, Mass. (Box 1, Volume I-A)
  - Nathaniel1 ATWOOD, MOREY, BARTLETT (Box 1, Volume II)
  - WARREN, Nathaniel3 ATWOOD, ADAMS, Nathaniel4 ATWOOD (Box 1, Volume III)
  - SHURTLESS, LETTICE, ADAMS, BUCK, MARSH, TURNER, HYLAND (Box 1, Volume IV)
  - Thomas1 CLARK, RING, LOTHROP, HAMMOND (Box 1, Volume IV-A)
  - Caleb5, Caleb6, Horatio7 ATWOOD (Box 2, Volume V)
  - Horatio N. ATWOOD Diary, 1892 (Box 2, Volume V-A)
  - SHAW (Box 2, Volume VI)
  - PERKINS, WISE, LONG, CONANT, HORTON, WALTON (Box 2, Volume VII)
  - CUSHMAN (Box 2, Volume VII-A)
  - ALLERTON (Box 2, Volume VII-B)
  - ALLERTON, NEVIUS, BEDLOO (Box 2, Volume VII-C)
  - DUNHAM (Box 2, Volume VII-D)
  - DUNHAM Royal Lineages (Box 3, Volume VII-E)
  - Adam1, Seth2, Enos3, Biblical Ancestors (Box 3, Volume VII-F)
  - Joshua1, Benajah2 PRATT, DOGGETT (Box 3, Volume VIII)
  - WATSON, HICKS (Box 3, Volume IX)
  - Henry1 COBB, James2 HURST, LEWIS, James3 COBB, HALLETT, HOLLEY, GORHAM (Box 3, Volume X)
  - Sylvanus4 COBB, BINNEY, BAKER, ROBINSON, HANFORD, HATHERLY (Box 3, Volume XI)
  - COBB, Binney5; SHAW, KNOWLES, RICH (Box 3, Volume XII)
  - Edmond1, John2 FREEMAN (Box 4, Volume XIII)
  - PRENCE, 1601-1652 (Box 4, Volume XIV)
  - PRENCE, 1653-1673 (Box 4, Volume XV)
  - BREWSTER (Box 4, Volume XVI)
  - DOANE (Box 4, Volume XVII)
  - COLE (Box 4, Volume XVIII)
  - Matthew1 PRATT; JOHNSON, HOLMAN, QUINCY, SHEPARD, TYNG, John6 PRATT, BOSWORTH, EDDY (Box 4, Volume XIX)
  - John6 PRATT (Box 5, Volume XX)
  - Abigail Adams, by Janet Whitney. Little, Brown and Company, Boston, 1948. (1 vol.) (Box 5, Volume XX-A)
  - American Statesmen: John Quincy Adams, by John T. Morse, Jr. Houghton, Mifflin and Company, Boston, 1882. (1 vol.) (Box 5, Volume XX-B)
  - Bosworth, Eddy (Box 17, Volume XXI)
  - Lewis7 PRATT (Box 17, Volume XXII)
  - ATWOOD, Homer (Box 17, Volume XXIII)
  - H. P. ATWOOD Desc (Box 17, Volume XXIV)
  - Homer P. ATWOOD (Box 17, Volume XXV)
  - FAY, John1 to Moses4 (Box 17, Volume XXVI)
  - FAY, Moses4; LEARNED, Giles (Box 6, Volume XXVII)
  - FAY; John5; John6, Edwin7 (Box 6, Volume XXVIII)
  - FAY; WHITING (Box 6, Volume XXIX)
  - NEWTON, Richard1 to Gershom4 (Box 6, Volume XXX)
  - NEWTON, Francis5 (Box 6, Volume XXXI)
  - NEWTON, Francis5 (Box 6, Volume XXXII)
  - CLARK, William1 to Simeon4; STRONG, HUBBARD, GRAVES, PARSONS, SMITH, BOLTWOOD, SHELDON (Box 6, Volume XXXIII)
  - CLARK, Asahel5, Silas6; HUBBARD, GRAVES (Box 7, Volume XXXIV)
  - FARRAR. FORBUSH, BROWN, CLARK (Box 7, Volume XXXV)
  - BROWN, Elijah of Newport, NH and Bridgewater, VT (Box 7, Volume XXXVI)
  - BROWN Families - New Hampshire; Vermont; Connecticut (Box 7, Volume XXXVII)
  - BROWN Families - Massachusetts; Connecticut (Box 7, Volume XXXVIII)
  - BROWN Families - Connecticut-Rhode Island (Box 7, Volume XXXIX)
  - SIMMONS, Dan of Bridgewater, VT (Box 7, Volume XL)
  - SIMONS - VT (Box 8, Volume XLI)
  - SIMONS - NH (Box 8, Volume XLII)
  - SIMONS - Massachusetts. (Book A) (Box 8, Volume XLIII)
  - SIMON-SIMMON - Massachusetts. (Book B) (Box 8, Volume XLIV)
  - SIMONS - CT Enfield Branch (Book I) (Box 8, Volume XLV)
  - SIMONS - CT (Book II) (Box 8, Volume XLVI)
  - SIMONS - CT (Book III) (Box 8, Volume XLVII)
  - SIMONS - RI (Box 8, Volume XLVIII)
  - SIMONS Index (Box 9, Volume XLIX)
  - BROCKWAY - CT, VT, NH, 1 notebook + 1 folder (Box 9, Volume L)
  - PRATT Misc., 1 notebook + 2 envelopes +1 folder (Box 9, Volume LI)
  - Plymouth Ancestors (Box 9, Volume LII)
  - Pilgrim Pictures - Plymouth, Mass. (Box 9, Volume LIII)
  - Massachusetts towns references; Plymouth - Pilgrim Data - Addenda (Box 9, Volume LIV)
  - Mayflower Pilgrims Data (Box 9, Volume LV)
  - Pilgrim John1 HOWLAND (Box 10, Volume LVI)
  - Jabz HOWLAND/THACHER (Box 10, Volume LVII)
  - Josiah3 HOWLAND (Box 10, Volume LVIII)
  - Samuel4 HOWLAND (Box 17, Volume LVIII)
  - SEAMANS, HOPKINS (Box 17, Volume LVIII-A)
  - Caleb5 HOWLAND, Book I, 17580-1790 (Box 10, Volume LIX)
  - Caleb5 HOWLAND, Book II, 1790-1839; SEAMANS; HOPKINS; WOOD (Box 10, Volume LX)
  - Caleb5 HOWLAND, Book III - Children, Descendants (Box 10, Volume LXI)
  - Caleb5 HOWLAND, Book IV - Children, Rev. James6 (Box 18, Volume LXII)
  - James6 S. HOWLAND, 1843 (Box 18, Volume LXIII)
  - James6 S. HOWLAND, 1844-45 (Box 18, Volume LXIII A)
  - Unnumbered folder containing correspondence and other materials re Atwood's genealogical research (Box 11, Volume ???)
  - Charles6 HOWLAND Book I (Box 11, Volume LXIV)
  - Charles6 HOWLAND Book II; RICH; FAY (Box 11, Volume LXV)
  - Charles6 HOWLAND Book III; Pittsford data (Box 11, Volume LXVI)
  - HOWLAND Silas C.7 Book I (Box 11, Volume LXVII)
  - Silas HOWLAND Box II (Also envelope containing photograph.) (Box 11, Volume LXVIII)
  - BEAN (Box 11, Volume LXIX)
  - WHITMARSH John1 to Thomas5. (Box 12, Volume LXX)
  - WHITMARSH Oliver6 (Box 12, Volume LXXI)
  - WOOD - Vermont (Box 12, Volume LXXII)
  - WOOD - New Hampshire (Box 12, Volume LXXIII)
  - WOOD - MA. Book I (Box 12, Volume LXXIV)
  - WOOD - MA. Book II (Box 12, Volume LXXV)
  - HOWLAND, Orvis8 (Box 12, Volume LXXVII)
  - HOWLAND, Orvis8 Book II (Box 13, Volume LXXVIII)
  - HOWLAND, Orvis8 Book III (Box 13, Volume LXXIX)
  - CRANDALL Book I (Box 13, Volume LXXX)
  - CRANDALL Book II; POLLOCK; SACKETT. (Also one envelope of photographs) (Box 13, Volume LXXXI)
  - KIBLER; McMURPHY; MURPHY; HATCH; EASTMAN; FLOWER; BARRELL; PIERCE (Box 13, Volume LXXXIII)
  - Howland Quarterly [I to XVI], 1936-1952 (Box 14)
  - Howland Quarterly [XVII to XXX], 1952-1966 (Box 14)
  - Howland Quarterly [XXX to XLI], 1966-1977 (Box 14)
  - MacBean Bean (Copies of The MacBean Register), 1966-1970 (Box 14)
  - MacBean Bean (Copies of The Clan MacBean Register), 1970-1976 (Box 14)
  - Folders containing genealogical letters and notes arranged as follows: (Box 14)
    - Atwood family, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Cooke-Mitchell-Washburn-Pratt (Box 14)
    - Cutler-Collar (Box 14)
    - Fisher family (Box 14)
    - Fisher-Stevens in America (Box 14)
    - Forbes, Canaan, CT (Box 14)
    - Robert C. Geer & Geer memorial material (Box 14)
    - Hannah2 Howland Bosworth (John1 Howland) (Box 15)
    - (Millicent J. Allyn) (Box 15)
    - Sarah2 Howland (Henry1). Mrs. Samuel Miner Anderson (Box 15)
    - Isaac Howland (Mrs. Ernest A. Benway) (Box 15)
    - Howland Hemphill (Mrs. C.J. Buckman) (Box 15)
    - Pilgrim John Howland (Mrs. Susan B. Clark) (Box 15)
    - Lionel Howland (Mrs. Julia A. Clews) (Box 15)
    - Arthur1 Howland Descendants (Arthur W. Damon) (Box 15)
    - Henry1 Howland (Mrs. Ralph M. Dean) (Box 15)
    - John4 Howland (Mrs. Robert F. Dean) (Box 15)
    - Mary (Howland) Gardner (Mary Decresenzo) (Box 15)
    - Leander & Abel Howland (Josephine Howland Gaunt) (Box 15)
    - Clark Howland (Richard H. Graves) (Box 15)
    - Solomon Howland (Mrs. Mary Gunn) (Box 15)
    - Paul Howland (Henry1 line). (Mrs. Michael Hanlon) (Box 15)
    - Waterman Howland (Mary E. Harrington) (Box 15)
    - Abraham Howland (Mrs. Douglas W. Heald) (Box 15)
    - Benjamin Howland (Dorothy M. Hendricks) (Box 15)
    - Benjamin Howland of Cape Cod (Box 15)
    - Daniel Howland (Box 15)
    - Garrold S. Howland (Box 15)
    - Henry1 Howland Line (Dr. Joseph E. Howland) (Box 15)
    - Arthur1 Howland (Mrs. Edward Kabelac) (Box 15)
    - Hope2 Howland (John1) (Box 15)
    - Humphrey Howland (Mrs. Henri J. Liva) (Box 15)
    - Howland Miscellaneous (Box 15)
    - Lydia2 Howland Brown (Percy B. Mettler) (Box 15)
    - Thomas Nye Howland (Harriette H. Otteson) (Box 15)
    - Carver Howland (David Quinn) (Box 15)
    - Desire (Howland) (Gorham [Mrs. Michael J. Ready]) (Box 15)
    - Howland Simmons, Woodstock (Box 15)
    - Joseph2 Howland (John1) (Mrs. R. F. R. Tolson) (Box 15)
    - Howlands of America Supplement, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Morse Society (Box 15)
    - Peck (Maternal Ancestry of Silas C. Howland research) (Box 15)
    - Smith, Azariah (Mrs. Earl R. Stanley; Carol Scarpone) (Box 15)
    - Westcott family (Box 15)
  - Genealogical References (Box 15)
  - Genealogical Sources (Box 15)
  - Senator John Howland (R-Vermont) (Box 15)
  - Maps: (Box 15)
    - “A Plan of Plimouth including Bays, Harbors and Island etc..”, map (Box 15)
    - New York State map (Folder Item 19 Oversize)
    - United States map (Folder Item 20 Oversize)
    - Windsor County, VT maps (Folder Item 20 Oversize)
    - “Vermont Maps” (Folder Item 21 Oversize)
  - John4 HOWLAND Book (Box 16)
  - [Descendant of John4 HOWLAND and Freelove HOWLAND] (Box 16)
  - John5 HOWLAND, RI and PA (Box 16)
  - [John3 HOWLAND] (Box 16)
  - Book II - John5 HOWLAND Descendants (Box 17)